NAJWANHASSAN

Halifax, NS, Nova Scotia B3K 1(437)-324-2221 - najwanhassan56@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A graduate in Computer Science, possessing three years' worth of experience in launching products and services into emerging markets, currently pursuing an IT Programming for AI degree at NSCC, expected to graduate in April. I am keen to apply my machine learning expertise within the Technology Industry. My background uniquely positions me to deliver impactful AI solutions that drive strategic business outcomes and competitive advantage of clients.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Leadership and teamwork: Leading a cross-functional team at FDA.
- Impact on efficiency: Improving collection and data processing speeds.
- Published a paper on GANs about deepfakes and it's effects on society.

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python, Java and C++.
- AI Focused Programming Languages: TensorFlow, Keras and Pytorch.
- Machine Learning Algorithms: Deep Learning, Neural Networks and NLPs.
- Data Analysis and Visualization: Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, SQL (MySQL & PostgreSQL)

and NoSQL (MongoDB & Cassandra).

WORK HISTORY

09/2021 to 06/2023 Safety Monitoring Personnel

FDA - Accra, Ghana

- Enhanced system performance by conducting regular monitoring and maintenance of equipment.
- Reduced system downtime by swiftly identifying and resolving technical issues.
- Streamlined data collection processes for improved efficiency in reporting.
- Collaborated with engineers to implement new monitoring systems.

09/2020 to 07/2021 National Service Personnel

FDA - Accra, Ghana

• Part of the COVID-19 vaccination in Ghana, uncovering customers' pain points and proposing holistic solutions tailored to delivering a delightful customer experience.

- Coordinated activities of call centers and provided training to improve skills.
- Observed employee performance and provided valuable feedback using online performance evaluation software.
- Created work schedules to provide quality service to customers as well as maintain employee satisfaction.

07/2019 to 09/2019 **Web Developer (Intern)**

Ghana Institute of Management and Public Administration – Accra, Ghana

- Designed and implemented a voucher generator for payment of fees online.
- Suggested ways of keeping the GIMPA website up to date with latest information.
- Took part in troubleshooting of technical issues to solve problems quickly and efficiently.

EDUCATION

Expected in 06/2024 Graduate Certificate: IT Programming for AI Nova

Scotia Community College - Halifax, NS

06/2020 Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

GIMPA - Accra, Ghana

CREATED A CNN FOR A HAND-DRAWN DIGIT RECOGNITION SYSTEM

With the goal of creating a reliable system for hand-drawn digit recognition, I created a Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) that can categorize handwritten digits with a high degree of accuracy.

CREATED AN ENVIRONMENTAL SENSORY NETWORK.

I also used my knowledge to build an environmental sensory network, interpreting and analysing data from several environmental sensors using machine learning methods.

CREATED A LIP-READING TRANSCRIPTION MODEL.

Developed an innovative lip-reading to transcription AI model designed to accurately convert silent speech video into text. Leveraged cutting-edge machine learning and computer vision techniques, including convolutional neural networks (CNN) and recurrent neural networks (RNN), to analyse and interpret lip movements. Through these projects, I was able to show that I was proficient in creating and putting into practice AI solutions for data analysis and picture identification tasks in the context of environmental monitoring.